

Contact

Mobile:

+49-17641460233

Email:

giridhargandi18@gmail.com

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/giridhargandi

Address:

 Am Europakanal 36, Erlangen, 91056, Germany.

Skills

- Design Thinking
- Project Management
- Leadership

Digital Skills

- MS office
- MS Power BI
- Python
- OpenWind
- Homerpro

Volunteering

- Member at Toastmasters international for public speaking.
- Volunteered for Akshara Educational and Welfare Society to teach underprivileged children.

Interests

- Calisthenics
- Volleyball
- Movies

Languages Known

- English (Proficient)
- German (Intermediate)
- Telugu (Native)
- Hindi (Native)

GIRIDHAR GANDI

MECHANICAL AND ENERGY ENGINEER

Profile Summary

Master's student with 3 years' experience in Energy Industry, specialized in Renewable energy technologies and their Integration. Holds a diploma from ESADE business school in entrepreneurship and management. Interested in business aspects of Power Systems, Energy markets, Storage, Management and Hydrogen technology. Actively looking for fulltime opportunities in the afore mentioned interests, where I can contribute my best for a greater good.

Education

Dual Master's in Renewable Energy by EIT Innoenergy

Double degree (2022 - 2024)

- 2 Year program taught at top European technical universities: KTH Royal Institute of Technology (Stockholm) and Universitat politècnica de Catalunya (Barcelona)
- Secured the Energy Impact Scholarship at the European institute of Innovation and Technology.
- Developed extensive knowledge of diverse renewable energy technologies, including Solar, Wind, Hydro, Biogas, Hydrogen and Fuel Cells, and Energy Storage, through rigorous coursework and hands-on projects during my MSc in Renewable Energy studies.
- Developed economy wide energy system models to study the pathways for energy transition.
- Has hands on experience in data analytics and machine learning applications for energy systems.
- Academic projects on Smart girds applications for digital transformation of energy systems.
- Participated in consulting case studies and hackathons organized by McKinsey and Bax and Company.

Esade Business School Barcelona

Diploma in Innovation and Entrepreneurship (2022 -2023)

- Entrepreneurship and New Venture Creation Project **Business development** of **Repurposing EV batteries** after degradation.
- Design thinking and Agile Project management.
- Creativity, Strategy and Innovation.

Amity University, India

Bachelors in technology (B. Tech) in Mechanical Engineering (2015 – 2019)

- 4 Year course which covers core topics of Mechanical engineering.
- Thesis: Conducted research for creating polymer composites from Dhak Plant to investigate its potential uses.

Work Experience

Master's Thesis at Siemens Energy – Germany (June'24 - Present)

- Developing an economy wide energy system model of Germany using PyPSA.
- The main aim of the thesis is to investigate economic and ecological benefits of hydrogen in the sector coupled energy system.

Project Engineer at Zhenshen Insulation - India (Feb 2022 - Aug 2022)

- Co-ordinated with International team for site projects in Indian projects.
- Created and **headed a team of 4 junior engineers** for monitoring the applications of Boro silicate brick lining
- Planned, managed resources and successfully executed 2 projects of flue can Boro silicate brick lining.

Project Engineer at Kuber Enterprises Pvt. Ltd. – India (June 2019- Jan 2022)

- Main responsibilities involved are planning project phases and managing site resources and manpower for the successful delivery of deliverables.
- Led a **chimney construction project** valued **€3.4 million** for a 660 MW coal thermal power plant for flue gas desulphurization.
- Managed multifunctional teams for the safe construction of two 150m tall chimney, mitigating heightrelated risks.